WILLIAN INACIO GONÇALVES

I started studying Information Systems in a 3-year technical course in the Federal Center of Technologycal Education. As soon as I finished the technical course, I entered a Bachelor's degree in Information Systems, at the same institution. At that time, I was co-author of a short article published in Brazilian Symposium on Multimedia and the Web (WebMedia), the main event of the theme in Brazil.

I have been working with software development since 2012. In this period I have worked in desktop, web and mobile projects, but int the last years, I have focused on web development and on developing skills like automated deployment and tests.

Today I continue to study with online courses, seeking to improve my skills.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

O2 Filmes

Cotober 2018 — Ongoing

♀ Remote

- Developing backend using Ruby on Rails
- Developing frontend using React
- Working on Etherpad customizable open source editor
- Writing integration and unit tests using Mocha, WebdriverIO, Enzyme and Rspec
- Testing and deploying software with Semaphore
- Monitoring logs with Sematext
- Working with Google Analytics
- Reviewing code
- Working by Kanban system

.NET Developer

Prion

September 2018 — October 2018

Nova Friburgo, RJ, Brazil

Developing and maintaining the Westcon Intranet using .NET Framework and SQL Server

Web Developer

Datahex

May 2017 — August 2018

Nova Friburgo, RJ, Brazil

- Developing backend using Node
- Developing frontend using Angular
- Developing mobile apps using Ionic
- Developing desktop application using Electron
- Deploying mobile app to Google Play store
- Integrating mobile app with other devices, such as thermal printer and QR code reader

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Backend Frontend Git Docker Database CI/CD UI/UX



SOFT SKILLS

Learning Potential Team Work
Organization Professionalism
Responsibility Punctuality
Dedication Simplicity
Communication Collaboration

STRENGTHS

· Development

Design Patterns OOP React]S

React Native Vue]s Ruby on Rails

RESTful APIs Graphql HTML

CSS Java C#

· Testing

Rspec WebdriverIO Enzyme

Jest Mocha

Databases

Mongodb Mysql PostgreSQL

Development Tools

- Developing software to import government-issued invoices
- Reviewing code
- Managing NoSql databases
- Working by Scrum framework

Web Developer

Crafters Innovation Studio

🛗 January 2017 — May 2017

- **♀** Remote
- Developing web applications using Ruby on Rails
- Testing software using Rspec, adopting 100% of software coverage
- Reviewing code
- Working by Kanban system

.NET Developer

R₂MS

- Nova Friburgo, RJ, Brazil
- Developing desktop and web applications using .NET Framework
- Developing user interfaces using WPF
- Developing web applications frontend using Node
- Integrating desktop application with fingerprint devices
- Developing software to import government-issued invoices
- Building and distributing installers for desktop applications
- Managing Mysql databases
- $-\,$ Experiencing different technologies, such as: C#, XML, HTML, CSS, SQL

EDUCATION

Technical Course in Industrial Computing
Federal Center of Technologycal Education, RJ, Brazil

£ 2009 - 2012

Bachelor's degree in Information Systems

Federal Center of Technologycal Education, RJ, Brazil

2014 – 2019

Undergraduated thesis: User Interface Prototype Generation from Agile Requirements Specifications written in Concordia

LANGUAGES

Portuguese English

